Happy to be here. I guess it's my first time in a long time giving a talk about something
that isn't about data science tools or data infrastructure, data systems, things like
that. Honestly, I mean, I was an AI skeptic for the longest time and didn't engage much
with these tools or systems. And, you know, suddenly coding agents burst onto the scene
and I would say that I haven't really written code in about a year, or at least not meaningful
code. And so that's definitely put me into a contemplative mood thinking about the future
of software engineering and what role there is for people like me today who have a lot
of experience building software and systems and what's going to be our role going forward.
But in general, you know, it's clear that, you know, we as developers are already writing
a lot less code. I essentially don't write code anymore. I think that's going to become
increasingly the norm for a large category of systems. There may still be certain specialized
systems, databases, things that require deep expertise and the agents don't know a lot
about where they're still going to be written by human hand. I expect that the DuckDB developers
are going to continue to write code by hand for a lot of things. But a lot of classes
of software aren't going to be written by people. And so that begs the question, what
is left for us to do? And the argument that I, you know, I will pose in this talk, and
I don't know that I will convince you of everything that I'm going to say, mainly my goal is to
provoke ideas and dialogue about these things, is that these three kind of human traits of
understanding the scope of what you're building, how to design it, how to architect it, and
taste what makes it good are really the most important things that are left. But I will
also argue that these were also the things that mattered the most in the first place.
And that coding was this annoying human labor that got in the way of actually building the
things. But if you didn't have these essential ingredients, it was very difficult to build
a piece of high quality production software. And there are many pitfalls along the way
that could result in creating software that fails to ship or falls apart under the weight
of its own bad decisions. And let's face it, we use a lot of software products every day
that simply aren't very good. I'm going to talk about that as well and what we're going
to do about it. You know, there are people in the software craftsmanship community that
have a lot spicier takes than I do. I followed Uncle Bob for going on 20 years since I read
his book Clean Code in the late 2000s. And he responded to Brian Armstrong's recent tweet
about cutting head count as a result of AI and having non-technical people shipping production
code. And he said, honestly, I don't think he knows what he's talking about. What the
agents give us is the ability to disengage from deep syntax, but they do not give us
the ability to disengage from modular design and architecture. You still need to be deeply
technical in these topics in order to produce good quality production code. I will say I
largely agree with this with some nuances. And so I'm going to wade into these topics
before I later in the talk, I'll move on and talk about some of the systems and tools that
I've been building for myself to fully embrace agentic engineering and to feel more comfortable
about using agents to produce production code. So if you've never heard about Fred Brooks,
he was at IBM and led one of the largest software projects of the 20th century, building OS360,
IBM mainframes. This led him to write the Mythical Man-Month in 1975, which you say,
wow, 1975 is a long time ago, 51 years. Still is enduringly one of the most cited and most
influential works on software management and software engineering in history. And even
today you're starting to see, you know, I wrote an essay about the Mythical Man-Month,
like Martin Fowler just wrote an essay about it. It is still influencing minds and it is
coming up more and more in today's context of agents carrying an increasingly large burden
of the software that we're writing. He wrote a follow-up essay to the Mythical Man-Month that
was also very influential called No Silver Bullet, which introduces, I think, a helpful
framework in thinking about software complexity that I will come back to and explain.
But if you've never read this book, and I admit that I have never actually read this book cover
to cover. I've mainly read excerpts and sections and quotes and ideas, but a lot of these ideas,
some of which have been lost and have to be relearned over and over again. But, you know,
Brooks's Law, the idea that adding manpower to a late software project makes it later,
it makes it later. It's one of those things that, you know, people forget and then they
have to relearn the hard way. I don't know if any of you have been in a company where a pointy
haired boss says, this project is behind, we need to hire engineers to make it go faster.
I'm usually the person in the room who's saying, wait, wait, like, have you read the Mythical
Man-Month? Like, are you sure that this is a good idea? Maybe the problem is actually that
you have the wrong people working on the project, not that you need to add people.
And so this idea of the surgical team that a small team of elite people outperform large teams
of average ones is also one of the reasons why startups can deliver innovations and disrupt
industries in, you know, short amounts of time and run circles around their much larger and more
well-equipped competitors. One of the reasons that adding people to a software project
can make it go slower is because of the communication overhead, which grows
quadratically with the number of people. And so, you know, a 20 person software,
20 person engineering team versus a five person engineering team, there's just a lot more overhead
in, you know, delegating work, splitting up tasks, going through design, getting everybody on the
same page. You need to introduce layers of management to keep people on track. And, you know,
the whole, you know, agile practice was created to try to mitigate some of these issues. And, you
know, I would argue that the practice of agile is practically dead today and any team that's still
having backlog grooming and sprint planning is doing it wrong. Another idea that comes from this
book is the idea that the difference between a working software, you know, project and a software
product that you can sell and can be maintained in production is roughly like an order of magnitude
in the amount of work. And, you know, now when we have agents producing, we have agents producing
software and it's alluringly simple to sit down with cloud code, build a brand new piece of
software and say, oh, looks good, I tested it, it works, like, let's ship it. And it's kind of
missing kind of that layer of work, which is described in this 9X gap that would be involved
in, you know, actually running that project in production over a long period of time and all the
problems that can come up along the way. And so, you know, so a lot of these ideas are summed up
in thinking about software architecture and software design is this notion of conceptual
integrity. And so it's the idea that when you look at a software project, you want it to seem
like it was designed by one mind. So like one kind of coherent set of ideas, even if there were many
people implementing and developing it. And so if you have a project that has a bunch of
disparate or like discordant ideas, then, you know, that can create a lot of problems as the project
scales. And so Brooks says, you know, if the project reflects one set of design ideas, it's
better than having many good but independent and uncoordinated ideas. And of course, nowadays we
have agents jumping in and adding lots of independent and uncoordinated ideas to all of our
software projects. So in the no silver bullet essay in 1986, Brooks introduced this idea of two
kinds of software complexity, the essential complexity, which is basically what the system
solves, how it needs to be designed in order to be a working solution for what you're trying to
build. And that involves the conceptual integrity and having a coherent picture of like these are
the essential set of features for this to be a complete system. If we take anything out, the
project is no longer a solution for what we're trying to solve. And then accidental complexity
is everything else that is introduced by our tools and processes and technologies that we're using
to build the system. And so that involves our programming languages, our build tools,
like all of our systems that do testing and QA and continuous integration, you know,
the boilerplate that's involved with interacting with databases and all that fun stuff.
And so agents are tremendously powerful tools for dealing with all of this accidental complexity
that comes up while you're building a software project. You can say, you know, hey, Claude, hey,
Codex, you know, hey, Gemini sometimes, go and refactor, you know, all of this code, change the
test framework, rewrite all of the tests. It's happy to dive in and attack and deal with all
of this complexity that is introduced by, you know, the tools and systems that you're using
to build the project. And I'm encountering this firsthand myself as I've largely moved on to use
other programming languages other than Python, which I will show you in more graphic detail in
a little while. I've never written a line of Go professionally or a line of Swift professionally.
And yet I'm, you know, in any given day, I might be slinging, you know, 5 or 10 or 20,000 lines of
code in these programming languages. I'm not an expert in, like, what are the right tools and
frameworks and libraries that I should be using in each language. But, you know, I do look at the
code and see whether, like, is there a lot of code duplication, code smells, classic refactoring
signals. And to be able to tell an agent, like, there's code duplication in this file or these
tests, like, seems like this test suite could benefit from test fixtures. And to be able to
work at that high level of being able to speak in the language of refactoring and clean code
and to be able to go and reformulate whole parts of a software project in small amounts of time
has given me, like, a tremendous sense of agency. And what used to be, like, I'd have to pick and
choose my battles of, like, do I really want to spend today refactoring this test suite? Usually
the answer is no. But now I can have, you know, the agents refactor my test suite while I'm having
lunch. And that's a nice thing. The downside, of course, is that when the agents are working on,
you know, the essential parts of the system, they have a difficult time distinguishing between
the essential complexity and the accidental complexity. And they also generate new kinds
of accidental complexity in doing the work that you need them to do. And so this could take the
form of, you know, creating the right, having the wrong domain model, like, the right, you know, the
wrong layering of classes or, like, failing to recognize that, you know, if you're building
something UI related that you have to explain to the agent, like, we're using, you know, this is the
model, this is the view, this is the controller. But if you don't explain that to them and articulate,
like, this is how the system should be designed, the default output in a lot of cases is just going
to be a hairball that becomes, you know, increasingly difficult for the agents to refactor.
And this gets worse and worse as time goes on because fresh agent sessions come into the existing
code base and they're just as happy to, you know, bolt another appendage onto the Frankenstein
rather than taking a step back and saying, okay, what is this code, how should this code really be
designed? You know, what types of, what are the right abstractions, like, the right layering of
components to make this easy to test and maintainable, easy to refactor, easy to think
about. So it's very difficult because, you know, the agents, they're, they've been, you know,
reinforcement learned and reward hacked to just want to solve the problem that you put in front
of them. And so if you need, if you want them to clean up and improve the quality of the code base,
generally you have to ask them to do that explicitly. They won't just do it on their own.
Another closely related idea to this that I, you know, I have to mention is the,
you know, different, different software engineering person, but Conway's law is the idea that the
organization, the software projects resemble the organizational structures that produce them.
And so, you know, this is also one of the reasons why small teams often outperform large teams
outperform large teams, because you have like a smaller group of people designing the whole system
thinking in a coherent manner. Whereas when you say, okay, this person is responsible for the
data plane, this, this, this you know, this team is responsible for the UI, this, you know, team
for some other part of the system, you end up having like a lot of, a lot of negotiation and
a lot of discordance and kind of the interactions between, between those systems. And that makes,
generally makes the software projects a great deal more complex and hard, hard to work with.
Another, another issue that I've seen is that I think a lot of people are experiencing the joy
of coding agents in the context of building greenfield software. So I don't know how many,
for me, it's like actually a great joy to sit down and make dir and get in it and launch a
fresh cloud code session and start and start building something. And you're creating files,
you're creating build systems, you know, you're, you're terraforming kind of in a godlike manner,
you know, with, with a wave of your hand. But that's a lot different from taking agents and
dropping them into an existing 3 million line production code base, which has been worked on by
a hundred people over a period of 10 or 15 years. And we've seen, you know, anecdotally that, you
know, agents struggle with these, with these large brownfield projects. But if you start a brand
new project with coding agents, and despite your best efforts, eventually there's going to come a
point where your lovely, delightful greenfield project is going to turn into a brownfield
project itself after, you know, a thousand agent sessions and something like that. And I don't know
exactly where that, like, where that crossover point occurs, my sense is that it's somewhere in
the, somewhere in the low hundreds of thousands of lines of code. Like I noticed that, you know,
just the feeling of getting things done in a 200,000 line fully agent developed code base,
it's just a lot different from like a 30,000 or 40,000 line code base. And a lot of that
has naturally to do with, you know, the agent context and just the overall complexity of the
system. And you can introduce, you know, memory, you know, memory layers and design documents and
to help provide affordances for the agents to be able to at least navigate the code base and spend
a lot of time calling tools and figuring out, like, what code should they be looking at? Like, what do
they need to understand to be able to do things? But still, it's like, just with the architecture
of LLMs, it's just fundamentally a problem. Like, there's kind of come a point where the code base
is big enough that the agents are going to start to have a difficult time doing what you need them
to do. And so, I would describe this as the, in Mythical Man Month, it's described for the human
aspect, the tar pit. So, it's the idea that you can see the beast struggling in and it looks as if
any of them could easily free themselves, but the tar holds them all together. And so, here, you
know, we might have, you know, at any given time in a project, you might have five different coding
agent sessions going on in different Git work trees. And they just, they don't really know,
you know, have a great deal of understanding about what, you know, each of the different
agents are doing and the decisions that are making. And so, you often end up with, like,
complex rebases and having to, like, redo or, like, rethink work because, you know, the agents are all
trampling on each other as you're trying to work in parallel and get things done. And it very much
resembles the same kinds of problems that occur in the human space of, you know, individual humans
you know, typing on keyboards and working on, you know, pull requests in parallel. And so,
you know, in this sense, you know, I do believe that we're, you know, continuing to accrue,
you know, a similar but slightly different type of technical debt, but we're doing it at machine
speed. And so, we're starting to encounter the kinds of system scalability, development scalability
problems that used to occur much later in the lifespan of a project. So, you could be starting
to have these issues after working on a project for only a week or two rather than, like, a year
or two. And so, that's just a new problem that we have to we just have to reckon with.
So, if you think about, you know, how cheap and easy it is to generate code,
it's easy to, you know, wake up every morning at, you know, 530 or 6 o'clock in the morning
and while you're making coffee to drop your first prompt and ask, you know, ask one of
the agents to build something. And the agents are happy to oblige. They, like, saying no is, like,
almost not in their, I think it's not in their system prompts. Like, they're not allowed to say
no, you know, unless you ask them to do something dangerous or illegal. And so, you know, if you ask
them to build something for you, it's, you know, relatively rare that they're going to push back
and say, like, no, that's not a good idea or, like, that's going to introduce, you know, too
much complexity or are you sure that, like, this is the direction that you want to go. And so,
essentially, you know, we are having, you know, we're turning into, you know, a lot of us were
individual contributors, you know, working with a tech lead or a software architect. But now we
are essentially all turning into architects or even product managers where our primary role is
saying no. And when the agent proposes to do something, we have to be able to recognize that
and say, no, no, pump the brakes. Like, I do not want you to do it. You do it like that. And if
you don't, well, the bad decisions will pile up and you're back to the tar pit. This begs the
question, how do you hold the agents accountable? It's hard. And you can certainly use agents to,
you know, do adversarial review and design and architecture review. But I think the human in
the loop still matters a lot. And I think this goes back to, you know, the point that Uncle Bob
was making in Uncle Bob's way that if you lack the technical expertise to recognize when the
agents have gone off the rails or have gone in a bad direction that's introducing a lot of unwanted
or unreasonable complexity in your system, you know, you're going to end up in just a giant
mess. And right now there's lots of non-technical or not very technical people who are using coding
agents to build software who are all going to be learning this the hard way and wondering why
they're having such a difficult time just making the software work. A lot of it will be found out
in production, I'm sure, when they're getting complaints from their users when things are broken.
And so, certainly, I believe there's, you know, a shift in the skills that matter now. Like,
I spent, you know, over 20 years writing code professionally, really priding myself on my
ability to write code, you know, my ability. I'm an Emacs user. So, like, I got really good at all
of the, like, key chords and, like, you know, being able to refactor code and navigate large
code bases really quickly and type and write the code. And now I essentially don't have to do that
anymore. And there's, but I do think that, you know, your ability to, like, build conceptual
integrity, visualize the problems that you're solving and what the shape of the solution looks
like, you know, is one of the most important skills that you can build. And I think that
software engineers, especially computer science students, are going to have to spend a lot more
time building this skill in a way that doesn't involve writing code. So, that's going to be,
you know, reading more code, like, looking at the architecture and design of systems so that
you even have the language to be able to express what you want to the agents.
Certainly, that, you know, the next skill, like, being able to explain and communicate with the
agents, if you can't, you know, clearly articulate how you want the work to be done, it's, you know,
agents will fill in the gaps with, you know, their own ideas about the way that things
should be done. But it may not be right. And if you can't recognize that, you could spend a lot
of time building a specification that creates, you know, creates things the wrong way or in a
suboptimal way. And so, I do think that increasingly, like, we're going to be engaging primarily with
specifications and less with the details of how to build things. And so, you know, and I'll talk a
little bit about this in a few minutes. But it's going to be a lot more than sitting down and
saying, you know, add a button, you know, add a button to this page. It could be more of, like,
okay, let's have a broader discussion about, you know, the big picture goals of what this software
does and, you know, its list of features, its non-features, so that you can build a detailed
specification, which can be then adversarially reviewed and turned into an implementation plan
and then implemented by a fleet of implementer agents and reviewers and all those things.
Essentially the kind of stuff that the factory fellow was just talking about in his last talk.
So, this all being said, the models are getting better. They're a lot better than they were six
months ago. And six months before that was a big shift. So, you know, it's possible that these
issues may go away as the harnesses get better and the models get better.
But I'm not sure. And I do think that from what I've seen, engineers who have deep technical
background and experience designing and building software are the ones currently who are getting
the most leverage out of coding agents and who are producing the highest quality software with them.
And so, that gives me some confidence that, you know, the agents getting better at conducting
software engineering tasks and implementing correct code, I'm sure that, you know, the code
that they're writing will get better and better and more and more bug free. But I struggle to
believe that they're going to solve these fundamental software design and scope and
taste problems, which have always been, you know, the devilishly difficult part where humans are
needed to make things that are good. So, I'll change gears a little bit and
talk about some related ideas that I've had to this. And I'll talk a little bit about my personal
agentic engineering stack. But there's a lot of software out there that isn't very good.
Probably a lot of it you use every day and it frustrates you. I know that it frustrates me.
Gmail.com frustrates me. Like, you know, most software products, as a builder of software,
whenever I encounter something that seems not good, I'm often asking myself, like,
what product manager thought that this was good, that this was okay to ship in this state?
And so, I do think that there is, you know, for individuals who have, you know, good design skills
and good taste, there is a tremendous opportunity to go and recognize, like, this old software,
which is created pre-AI, is bad. Let's make something good. And I would challenge everyone
in the room, there's really nothing stopping you from doing this. And so, if you encounter
software products in your life that, you know, they're not good, you don't have to accept them
the way that they are. And I believe it's, you know, kind of incumbent on all of us to
kind of embrace that challenge and be willing to reject the, you know, the status quo or at least
the status quo pre-2026 and undertake work to build software projects that are good or at least
better than the ones that we have. And because it used to be that, you know, the excuse was that
it's hard to build things. Like, well, we would make it better, but we would have to spend a lot
of money on engineers to write code to make it good. But now that that excuse is gone, that
generating the code is free, the only excuses left are that you don't know what is good. Like,
you don't know, you know, you don't know what's the right thing to build, and you can't recognize
when it's good. And I think it's generally some combination of both. So, kind of back to the,
you know, the product manager who thought, you know, the current state of Gmail search is acceptable.
And so, you know, myself, like, I've, you know, embraced this completely and, you know, about six
months ago, I went down the rabbit hole and it's like, okay, you know, it's time to build. Like, I
spent a lot of 2025 in an existential crisis about, like, my role and, like, is my career
as a software engineer over? Are the agents just going to be doing everything without me in the
loop? And, you know, by about October, November, I was looking around, I'm like, agents are pretty
good, and yet the software is not getting better very quickly, you know, very quickly. I should do
something about that. And so, I've been, you know, been working, you know, day and night, you know,
largely seven days a week, maybe not the most healthy lifestyle generating code across a bunch
of programming languages. One thing that's interesting is you can see a discrete point
at the end of January where I became a former Python programmer. And so, you can see that delta
at the end of January where I made up my mind to essentially delete almost all of my Python code
and port it to Go. And so, I now largely consider myself an agentic Go programmer. But I want to
talk about, you know, some of what my experience has been like going down this rabbit hole and
some of the tools and systems that I'm building to try to
and systems that I'm building to try to give me,
essentially retain my agency where I am able to conduct
a almost factory-like software process of building specifications,
implementing those, doing quality verification similar to the factory talk.
This also has influenced my choice of programming languages,
and so I wrote an essay earlier this year talking
about human ergonomics and agent ergonomics.
One of the reasons why we use Python today is
because it was an amazing programming language for humans to read and write,
and why I got so motivated about building Pandas was like,
wow, Python is an amazing programming language if only it could do data well.
Fortunately, that ended up being a good bet and a good way to spend my time for many years.
But now, agents don't care as much about whether Go is annoying to write or not.
They care about whether they can compile and test really fast.
There's an aspect of distributing the software.
Do you have to carry around a virtual machine?
How do you install your dependency stack?
Being able to build a static binary and just
CP it onto a server on your tail scale network,
build it in three seconds and deploy it in four seconds,
is a really nice feature of the language.
These old ideas of human ergonomics,
readability and the ease of writing code and working with code,
and your text editor or your IDE,
they just don't matter as much anymore.
Some of the runtime infrastructure layer running our code,
the JVM is even more of a burden today than it was a few years ago.
You can obviously have the agents install the JVM and all that,
but static binaries are really nice.
I think that languages like Go and Rust that produce static binaries
are prime beneficiaries of this new agent ergonomics.
I also think that because of the fungibility of programming languages,
and frameworks, and the top part of the application stack,
that this also is causing more value to be pushed down the stack.
The things that are lower in the stack are the things that are still hard to build.
I struggle to believe that agents could be set to work and
could rebuild DuckDB.
Maybe somebody will do it someday,
but we're not close to that,
and those developers are still writing code by hand.
Hannes told me himself.
This is interesting in the sense that it does make
all of these fundamental systems that power applications even more valuable,
whereas the language user interface layer
is increasingly fungible and doesn't matter as much,
because agents can tear it down and build something new.
You want to change the programming language?
Fine, let's do that.
I don't even describe the way that I work now as vibe coding,
because I feel like vibe coding has become this pejorative,
like, yeah, I don't write the code,
I don't read the code either.
But that's not the way that I work.
Jesse Vincent, who created superpowers,
he gave me permission to reuse this quote,
which is from a private text thread.
But the difference between vibe coding and
agentic engineering is planning, architecture,
and caring about the output.
I'll tell you a little bit about what I've been doing
in my token maxing adventures.
I've burned something like a billion tokens per day the last 30 days.
I'm a little bit slower since I'm here at the conference,
conference Wi-Fi and things like that.
But I am a superpowers user,
and if you don't use superpowers,
which is I think the most popular
spec-driven development skills framework out there,
I highly encourage you to check it out.
It's how I get everything done now.
But around superpowers and spec-driven development,
I've been building a collection of open-source projects to try to
bring sanity to my world of agentic engineering.
These buckets are code quality assurance,
session intelligence, development, visibility,
observability, and project management.
There's many skills frameworks.
This one is good.
I think the idea is that it brings discipline to your planning process.
So first, clarify what you want to build,
answer a lot of questions about the design.
It presents the design in clear stages where you can read this.
Human, make a decision.
Is this the right design? That's your opportunity.
That's where you can add your value to make the right design decisions
because the spec will then be created based on those design decisions.
When the spec is created,
you can review the spec,
you can have other agents review the spec.
But eventually, you convert that into an implementation plan
which takes a long time to implement.
So one of the values of superpowers that allows you to
specify and plan a lot of work
upfront in these spec development design review sessions,
and then you can kick off
the sub-agent driven development and go take a walk or something.
I actually had a superpowers plan that took 14 hours to implement.
So sometimes, I find myself late at night,
I got to get my plan implementing before I go to sleep.
So I have something to look at in the morning.
But using these frameworks,
if you use them as is,
they do reviews that assert spec conformance and to an extent code quality.
But there's still a lot of bugs and problems in the generated code.
In the factory talk,
he's talking about Claude being not a good code reviewer.
I agree. The GPT-5 line of models is
a much better code reviewer, code validator.
So I found myself in the beginning of January asking
CodeX to review every commit that Claude was generating.
After a minute, I was like,
this should just happen automatically.
Why do I even have to ask?
So that was how RoboRev was born.
So now, I have agents generating code,
and my mantra is like every line of
generated code gets reviewed at least once,
usually four or five times before it ever lands into a production code base.
This is a system that I built to make all of that possible.
So somebody from the community said,
catches issues that I would have shipped otherwise.
I tend to rush things and this project keeps me honest.
So one of the core concepts is that rather than
reviews happening in the ephemeral agent session,
the reviews all go into a ledger and they have to be explicitly closed.
So it could be an agent closes the review or you close it yourself.
But you don't want to do a code review and for
the output of that code review to be lost like tears in the rain.
So you want to explicitly say like,
I read this either you or the agent looked at this code review,
you addressed its feedback,
and then you closed out the review.
So now four months later,
I've gone through something like 20,000 code reviews and RoboRef.
So it truly is like a continuous autonomous code review system.
I also found that it was frustrating like losing track of all my agent sessions,
and there are a lot of half-baked versions of agents view that were built.
So I wanted to create a unified session database for every coding agent,
full-text search, analytics about tool use,
token spend, where am I spending?
If I were paying API rates,
where would I be spending money?
There's a bunch of these projects.
I think this one's pretty good.
So if you're interested in this and it doesn't have something you want,
please come and drop a pull request.
I will review your pull request.
I did have the misfortune of
deciding that I needed to build my own issue tracker after
having beads delete half of my code base three or four times.
So I tried a bunch of
the lightweight local issue trackers and didn't find anything that I liked.
So a couple of weeks ago,
I started building Kata,
which I encourage you to check out.
It's just a SQLite database.
There are some stuff in it for issue federation,
but it's very helpful for agents to be able to have issues,
where they can leave comments and keep track of
the state of understanding that issue as they're working on it.
So it's another place where agents can record things aside from
a collection of scattered and disorganized markdown documents,
which is their default.
As we all know, GitHub has been falling apart.
Barely works half the days.
After a while, I just stopped going to GitHub
because you click on the pull request tab.
It says there's 27 pull requests,
but there's only two showing them.
So it's like, how do you even get work done on this platform?
So I decided to basically build a new UI for GitHub.
It uses the GitHub UI.
So now this is, I don't go to github.com anymore.
I use Middleman for keeping track of all my projects,
all the activity, I merge pull requests,
I comment on issues, I look at code reviews.
We're building some other stuff in this project.
So if GitHub is frustrating you,
this is what I use.
I'm sure a lot of people are going to be building
their own slightly different version of this to support their workflow.
I've tried out a bunch of the parallel agent managers.
I do currently use Superset,
not Apache Superset, but superset.sh.
It's got a lot of bugs.
If anyone in the audience is from Superset,
please fix the bugs that I've reported, please.
I can put up a pull request,
but you won't merge it, so it's fine.
Just fix the bugs.
But I do a lot of work in this system,
and so at any given time,
I might have 20 or 30 get work trees on my machine,
and especially when I'm dealing with inbound pull requests,
to be able to go from pull request number,
to get work tree, to hey Claude,
run RoboRev and fix what's wrong with this PR,
and then I landed in Middleman.
So that's how my process works in collaborative development.
So I'm running right up on time,
and we've got a few minutes for questions,
but I hope to provoke some thoughts
about the future of software engineering,
and I fully embraced this after being a skeptic
for the longest time, and I'm having a lot of fun,
and I think the fact that we get to build tools
while we're doing it to figure out how to do this better
makes it even more fun as a long time tool builder.
So thanks for listening,
and look forward to your questions.
Thank you.
Well done.
So I'm Frances Stegman,